Hello. Hello. Hello.
Good evening. Good evening. I'm
good evening, bro.
Am I Am I seeing you after a very long time. Were you not there
or were you there?
Yes. Yes, yes.
Were you on a break or something?
Yeah, I went for a vacation,
so I just came back on Monday.
Oh, very nice. Very nice. Yeah.
Uh, did you catch up with the previous sessions which you were doing?
Yeah,
yeah. We'll be trying to commit all the things.
OK,
OK, OK,
so it's good to have you back.
Good evening.
I was
a milestone one.
Were you all able to do it?
Did you find any difficulties?
Did you try the trick for baking inputs Which I told you
I mean restructuring the key and the value and all that stuff.
Did you all try someone? Did someone try that at least,
or did you just directly set the values for, uh,
both the or all the three inputs which were there?
So
and all all the tests are passing.
And Vikash,
which which you plan to have OK?
Oh, ok. Ok, ok.
What did you find?
Any test for this being very restrictive in any any of the approach,
something like that.
Like we had this problem with, uh, Q
dynamic and all that. Was there any particular test which was causing a problem?
It passed smoothly.
OK, brilliant.
Yeah,
but But, uh, like, I was a little bit struggling to add spin out like I was
trying not to completely figured out how to implement it correctly.
Like how to, uh, know how to, like, give a gap of some time to load the spinner. Uh,
I can understand that,
Uh, actually, you will be able to like, because that's a material U, I element,
right.
So once you are,
um, a bit
a bit a bit more comfortable with working with those kind of elements.
Uh, there will be something which you might, you know,
encounter which would help you style
the material
elements. You know very well. So there's something
called us,
um, create styles or something like that right
in in.
So we'll not be covering that, actually,
because that becomes a as an advanced use case.
So for now, you can, you know, just figure out using which element you want to style.
Um, using the
inspect element or something. Or maybe if you want, you can also use, um, important,
um, tag for that as well. If you want to post
something
but the right way, which I
suggest is using their, um,
theme
for styling the components.
You will get there. Don't worry.
Yes, This is actually the way. Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, no, that is actually the way. So,
um, something which I would you know, Which I will tell you all today, right?
When you have, like, all your naming conventions,
right when you're naming all these functions or states or something like that,
right.
It's better to suppose if, for example, if you have any, um,
a bull in values. Right. So it's better to have kind of a verb in front of the word,
right? I suppose if it is loading right, so it should be
is loading, right?
And if it is, suppose, um, for example,
um
um,
maybe it's like it. So something has something like, uh, a component has
something or has not something. So you can, you know, add,
um, suppose has buttons or has, uh, input something like that.
I suppose if you want to use it.
So it's better to have, um, kind of
verbs in front of it, because that becomes a very good naming convention.
And the way where I'm getting this is,
uh,
so here.
Right. I'll copy this for you.
This becomes a very
nice way to
name your components
or or or name your, uh,
props, actually.
Right.
This a cor or
state or whatever. You can use this particular thing.
Should we start? We have only 20 people in here very less
announced for today.
By this time.
Hey,
you
Things should start now. I believe
I
What do you
What do you mean
and starting?
And people join and they,
you know,
got
it, I believe.
OK,
are people ready? Should I start?
Listen in the chat, if you are ready with your code sandbox
to start coding for today's session.
Yes.
OK, Brilliant. Brilliant. Brilliant.
Oh,
so hello and welcome to Session five of Man one sprint.
And today in this session, we'll be dealing with two main things, right?
One is the lists and keys. Very important topic,
Uh, and very much, you know, confusing and, uh,
as well as you know, a lot.
Uh, more conventions. You learn here, right?
Like last time we learned the convention of using internally operators
to either show or remove an element.
And you also learned about what the and operator is, Right, So So you can, you know,
basically perform.
And,
um,
you can add bullion expressions with JSX so that, um,
it it it decides whether to show the element or not show the element
similar way we learn something, Uh, if you want to, you know, populate, um,
a list or something like that, right?
From an R A Maybe, uh, which is a very fairly common use case. Right.
So you're getting you'll be getting data in
json format.
Uh, that json format data will actually be, you know, used to show, like,
to to display things on the screen.
And that's where the lists come in.
And thing which goes hand in hand with list is react keys. Right.
So react keys is another very important topic
which you should know to avoid unpredictable outcomes.
When you're, you know,
uh, using the lists and all right,
and then we'll learn something. What is called a side effects Along with
which hook to use for side effects.
OK, the side effects is another very big topic of its own
right, and you'll see how,
uh, the hook will, which we'll be using Spoiler alert. It's called the use effect.
Right?
So when we'll be using that kind of hook, you'll see that it can perform, You know,
a lot of operations which you use to split
into three different life cycle methods into just one.
I hope you're all excited to start.
Should be
Yes.
OK,
starting with this
key. Right?
Um let's start. Let's start by doing something right?
So let's just start with an activity so that we can you know,
um
understand why we would, you know, require a better way of doing a thing.
OK, I'll give you a starter code.
Uh,
OK,
so one thing which you can do is
starter code would be
this
right?
So create a component. Uh, SRC slash session four or session five, basically right.
We are end of one session behind on the slide deck.
Uh, always
so. SRC slash section five
slash list dot Js
with the given starter code in the chat.
OK, once you're done plus one in the chat for me, OK?
Are the people done
OK.
Mhm.
And then in your
in your in your ok,
so in your app dot Js Now you need to
display the list component right for each element in superheroes,
right?
So there are three elements in superheroes, basically. Right.
So what you need to do is basically use this list component three times.
Kind of because you have three elements and then pass.
Send the values as props
right to the list component, as you can see on the list component.
And it takes the props. Right.
And in the props, it also, you know, takes the name or whatever.
Right? So what you can do is, uh, since it takes the name in the prop, right?
What you can do here is you can pass the
superhero
zero name superhero 01 name, superhero, two name and all that
to the list component
again, right?
Set the name Property two,
superhero name.
Right?
And
once you're done,
you would be seeing something on the screen. So let me just
also get the starter code from here.
Yeah,
I hope everyone understands the question which I am
getting at,
so let's do Js look something like this,
right?
And I believe because we are using JavaScript, right?
I always prefer to restructure the crops.
Right, Because we cannot know what the crops would be coming in,
so that becomes a bit difficult. Honestly.
Right.
So
now what you want to do here is once you have this in place,
I believe people can take in the name,
right, And then you can display the name here. Right?
Ok,
so So this is the list component which you can see. You can have the name right.
Or either you can have props here instead.
Right? Or either you can be structured using name,
whatever whatever feels right to you,
right? Same goes with here. So if you're using props, it will be props dot name.
If you're using this kind of syntax, it will be just name.
OK,
so once you're done with this,
go into your app dot Js
right.
And, uh,
use this, uh,
use
this particular
array right
to
I.
I don't pass the name here in in for each
of the superheroes into a list into the list component.
Does that make sense?
So you basically would you want to display
the
list
in there. OK, let me
control C
Control V
See
Right.
And here what I want is
a
list component,
right?
And I since I want to display three names,
basically I would want to have three of them.
Ok,
Does that make sense to everyone?
What? What I'm getting at
now.
So here, if you have your superheroes, right?
So what you would want to do is you want
to pass each of the superhero name into the list,
OK?
And then you'll probably be seeing something on the screen as well.
So right now I can see these,
but I cannot see the name. Right. So I need to pass the name as well
in the list, right? So list can take a prop as name,
right? So just pass the prop. And once you're done,
uh, plus one in the chat.
OK?
OK, cool. Cool, cool.
Brilliant. Can you see the name? And they tick in front of it
already?
If you can see this wide in the chart,
everyone who can see the name
along with the tick in front of it. So what? What? What I'm planning here to do is name
and then what? What I would do is superheroes.
And for the first superhero I would have to
use superhero zero dot name something like that,
right?
And similarly for other superheroes as well,
I'll have to use maybe one or maybe two,
right,
and close this bracket as well.
So it does not
cause any problems.
Can everyone see something like this in front of them?
Yes or no?
So once you start passing the names, right,
so,
by the way, in the list, right.
OK, so the benefit of Des structuring I'll I'll come to it.
Uh, first, if you can answer this question so in the list, right.
What is the value of E target or check the note for a checkbox?
Generally, can you Can you let me know about that?
So here, if we have this, uh, you know, input, right?
And if we are having,
you know, checked here, can you Can you find out what the check is
telling us
regarding this?
It may become so long
so you can understand what? What it is bringing in
OK. The
bull
to a false OK,
So if the event was triggered when the checkbox was checked, right?
So
either target or check is basically giving you up
if it is checked or not, right. A true or false value.
Right?
So now what happens is,
uh I suppose suppose what we want to do here is,
um
maybe if if if this is checked or not right,
we we can we can we want to find if it's checked or not.
The reason what what happens here is
now, if suppose in in this scenario right in this scenario,
uh, which what would we have
here? Right.
So here we were passing, you know, list one like the first name,
the second name and the third name.
Suppose if there are, like, 101,000 names in the list,
you know,
this would become very practically impossible to write 1000 names under it.
Does that make sense, people?
So if if I have a lot of names, right, so for now, I just have three names.
A fairly simple thing to do
but suppose in in.
In any case,
if I have 1000 names or 100 even if I don't know how many names will be there,
right. For example, sometimes the API returns this R A with 10 names.
Sometimes they return with 25 names. Sometimes something else.
How many should I actually go about putting here? Right, So I don't know about it yet.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Yes or no?
So So So So how long will I go about doing 0123 and all that? We don't know it yet.
OK,
so in that scenario,
right,
What we can do is we can instead,
for one, what you can do is we can start by replacing the J six that you already have
for a list
with this kind of version,
OK? And see if it works or not.
I mean, well, we we we are building up to that.
OK, just don't get spoilers to people already.
OK,
so
so try to try to write something like this and see if it works or not.
OK, so put put your, uh JSX.
You know, these three things inside
an array and see if it works or not.
OK?
And the way you put this inside an array
is, uh, and and put it inside.
JSX is using the curly braces because you You need to write curly bases to,
you know, insert javascript in between JSX Yes or no?
I hope you remember this from the last session. At least
that if you want to put in JavaScript inside JSX you need to use calibrations
and we can have an A a as well as as you. As you will see. OK,
so once you're done plus one in the chart.
If that does make sense to you
if it still gives you the same result basically
OK,
so is the Is the page you you saw as being correctly displayed right now.
Is that fine?
So what we wanted to do here is I will just basically go ahead and put this inside an R a
right,
and put commas in front of it.
OK?
And also
put this whole thing inside the braces.
OK,
so once I do, this
is
the reactor is basically smart enough to, you know, pass the,
uh array
and display the U. I elements inside it.
So there's no more, uh, doing, you know,
for each which thing which we used to do with normal JavaScript, right?
Do you remember that?
So we used to have an array, and then we used to have four each.
And then we used to append each element again
and again for each of the elements inside the
array and all that stuff which we used to do with export. Right?
Do you remember export?
Right. So in export, we had to do all this, right? So we had the,
uh, stuff which was there in the magazines array.
Then we went through the loop, and then he started doing all this.
Aria
is pretty smart enough to pass that array and understand it.
It has some, uh,
HTML element inside it or or some JSX inside it and to display it accordingly.
OK,
And can you think of some other ways of generating this kind of
JSXR A from superheroes,
I suppose if you have, uh, So So? So I'll give you a hint. Right?
So the hint would be maybe using, you know, the R a
and then creating a new array from the existing array,
which has the external elements.
Right?
So
how How we generally used to do that
to to create a new array from the existing array,
applying some function, some property onto the onto each element.
What was what was the way, which you used to do it.
OK, so just if you just had to directly copy it was spread
philtre,
uh, would be used. Maybe if you want to, you know,
um, philtre out some things, right? But we want each element to have to be to be
mapped to something directly.
OK, so for the first element, I want a list element, uh, you know, having a
super hero zero name, right? And then the second list element.
I also want something like that third list
element I want also want something similar,
right?
So with the map method, we can return a new array
right, Which we where we can map the existing thing, you know, existing array,
which we have
to
the JSX elements directly.
OK,
Can you rewrite your app component using map? Would you be able to do that?
So what you essentially want to do is if you want to get this
a a basically
right.
So the way you would get this a A is basically applying map on the superheroes, right?
And then, for each of the item,
you need to
uh, in
inside the map function, you need to return AJ SX right.
Which has name as item
like item dot name or something like that,
right? Does that make sense to everyone
or not?
You can write a function for that
or you can write, uh, you know, a constant for that or whatever. Like you can.
You can have a new,
um, a
created and you can pass it inside this
once. You do that, uh, share with me. The code that you wrote
right as well as your return function
Return
statement.
OK, so superheroes map. OK, very nice. Very nice.
So this is where where have you written this? Is this inside? Uh, via
And then is this inside your return? Or is this somewhere else like
Ra? Like someone did earlier?
I guess
Raviraj did right,
Ok,
Mhm.
Other people. Uh, have you done
a
group prachi
they had done
Yes.
Share your code with me as well.
I would also want to see that,
uh,
all of you should share your code in the chat. I mean, that is one way
which would help you to,
you know, improve your code quality as well
OK, OK, I see. I see.
Very nice. Very nice. Very nice.
So instead of having this right,
uh, we can have something like like people did.
And I'll tell you the drawbacks between both of these.
But for now, let's let's go with this. Superheroes
right dot map.
And then for each of the item,
what I want to do is, uh, return a list
right
where the name should be.
Item dot name.
OK,
I hope this makes sense
to everyone.
Is there anything which
it's causing a problem here?
Superheroes do
map
and
item, and I want to
OK,
right. And here I can. What I can do is I can just return the names,
right?
I believe this would work.
Yes,
does it?
OK,
but now what I can see is this So So?
So can anyone tell me one drawback with this kind of approach
of writing it here above and not inside it directly
or is the same? Is it the same as you know, writing it here or writing it here
and just exploring right II? I would also explore the answer with you as well.
It is something new for me as well, right.
But II, I would
prefer to write it inside this return
rather than here.
So any
any hints on why I would want to do that?
Anyone
let that be? Let that warning be for now.
Yes, You're
going in the right direction. I believe so.
In the case of re render, what will happen?
Ok,
for now I can see it's
pretty much working, right.
That is something which I was wanting to look at, right.
So I believe if if you put it,
you know, um, outside here, Right.
This thing will be calculated every time
this tree is made,
right,
so
and
are right in in this particular scenario.
So whenever we are, you know, triggering a render, what will happen is this will run.
This is
fine. This is assignment, right? But this is a calculation, right?
Kind of, you know, creating a new area out of our existing one.
This is this is some calculation which, uh, reactors are forming.
But since it is not inside the return right,
what will happen is it will calculate it again and then like,
like the whatever the value is, it will put it here.
So No matter if you're even changing this or not,
any change will just trigger the recalculation of this whole array.
Now, I suppose there are 1000 names. Or maybe if it's an infinite list, right?
If if you are
simulating a list, which is, you know,
um,
having maybe lacks of,
um uh
of of entries in here, then this calculation will become a bit heavy.
And since javascript is working one by one, right, it might
cause some issues. Right
When you're entering your page again and again, does that make sense to everyone?
Like, are you putting it here? 11 caveat can be that it will be calculated again
each time. This, um, whole thing is done, right, IIII.
I don't have any solid way of checking it for now,
but this is something which I can tell from conceptual examples.
Right.
But
if if I find a better way of and like helping you, you know,
get through this and I'll definitely
go about doing it
here What? What's happening is
in this particular scenario,
what's happening is
this is, you know,
being done by react. OK,
so this is something which is calculated by react and once
made into these elements and listen to these elements are changing.
Right?
Um
it will not touch these particular
elements as far as I think.
Right?
So
one thing which we may do quickly if
it allows us
is
suppose Let's add a button in here right
button.
And
in this button, what I can do is on click
one clip
console dot log, click.
And,
uh, what should I name this button
button?
OK,
and if I open it in a new window, let me see if something happens.
so right now I have this
And if I am clicking it,
Hm
there is Maria
Tools
component
settings
I like
There's already some problem with the react will not be
working perfectly fine. I will not be able to show you the example till I
make this list perfectly fine,
But OK, I'll, I'll go ahead and do that later. Actually,
OK, I was trying to bring up some example to see if,
uh basically if I click on the button
if all these things enter again or not, Right,
So that is something which I was trying to look at,
but OK, no worries. I. I try to do that later,
OK? So this would be actually
a right way.
Right?
Uh, console dot Log in a map.
Uh,
maybe, Maybe, but Reactor is telling me some other
error. Right? So
first we will get to that error, we'll understand what that error was,
right. And then we'll come back to it.
OK,
so now,
once we I hope everyone understands how we are able to do this this particular thing,
Yes,
food.
So now we can, like, render any number of elements dynamically now, OK,
so once we have an A a, we can practically go ahead and, you know,
render any number of elements dynamically.
OK,
so
why did we not have superheroes as a state variable?
This was one question which I popped in, popped into my mind.
So superheroes was kind of a constant thing right in here instead of having you know,
a state as a state variable like superheroes and said superheroes equal to you state
and then this value
or something like that.
And any guesses on why
we did not
went to that?
So this this is something which can be asked you during an interview at the
so once you're going in an interview, Uh, an interview might ask you that.
Why would you like when? At what point of point of time would you
use, uh, state variables to store a value?
And at what point of time would you use, you know,
local variables to store the value or something like normal variables?
Any guesses on this one? One?
Yeah. OK, nice. Nice answer.
Any other, Any other answers? Any other speculations here?
Ok, we has another Interesting,
but we don't want to give the user the control over this fair point.
Right?
OK, ok, so the She also says that,
um if you have to update the data, then only it is needed. Right?
So superhero elements aren't changing here, right? If you if you need,
uh you know, if you use state if you want the U I to render on state change, right?
So right now,
since Super Hero is already fixed in in our approach
for now we don't want the U I to render again
right? Super state changes the U. I must
like
to
Yes, um,
in the last session we did that. I believe
so When when when there was a U I change the whole, um,
like return was you know,
whole function was called again basically right whole function was done again.
So right now we do not want that
Whatever you are looking at here is like normal superheroes which are fixed.
You know, we are not getting it from an API. We are not
allowing it to change, you know, over time. Hence we are keeping it as a fixed value.
OK, so that was one reason why we did not have it as a state video video.
OK,
does that make sense?
Does that make sense to everyone
or not?
So your answers were somewhat right. I mean,
I think you're all getting ready for
this kind of interviews. If you appear for it
right
so slowly and get
you, you get that.
OK?
Something which I'll give you now. OK, let let me put
uh, let
let me give you some starter code. Ok?
So let me give you this starter code.
Put this
or or basically I'll give you the whole starter code for the app.
OK?
Use the starter code for the app, which I've just shared.
Uh ignore the above one. Right? If you can,
please.
Right.
Use the use the starter code below. Right, which I have just shared. Right.
OK,
once you are done plus one in the chart. So this you replace your
app with this particular thing? Ok,
I will also do it
so I will change my app
so
to this
And I also have to call you state from you.
Um
OK,
this is very painful that I have to
the move
see again and again
Mhm,
No!
OK,
so this would be your starter code. Once you're done, just let me know, OK?
This could be the starter code which you're looking at
once you're done, just let me know.
Plus one in the chat.
Once you're done with the starter code,
you don't need to understand what it's doing for now.
OK? How we are getting all this function and all that
Don't need to worry. Worry about it.
Uh, lists
as well. Ok,
so this is the list
once you're done plus one in the chat. Once you are done with this,
I
hope the pace is fine for everyone.
Was it fast or slow? It fine.
OK,
once we're done with this, just let me know, OK?
Listen, in the chat
so that I may know that you are you are ready with the starter code
and we will see something interesting going on in here. OK,
so basically, what if if I have to quickly explain this, what would happen here is,
uh this function will essentially just
shuffle this data right, which is in superheroes and then set the, uh,
shuffled data into superheroes.
OK,
so we're starting with some data
right
in here,
and then you want, uh, to shuffle it using a button.
This function is essentially just shuffling it right?
It comes from this particular
link
if you want to visit it,
right,
and, uh,
I hope everyone's ready with this.
So use this version of app dot Js,
which allows to shuffle the order of the check boxes.
Right.
Shuffle a shuffle button and it's
and
it's on click handler. Right Will be there.
And clicking the button shuffles the super superhero state elements.
OK, does that make sense?
And superheroes will be at stake.
Check the 1st 1st element displayed
OK,
and then try clicking the button to shuffle the order of element displayed.
Would you be able to do that?
Because the 1st, 1st of all, I have the winter soldier. Ok,
the second is iron Man. Third is black widow.
So in my first one, if I check it and if I click shuffle A right,
you do it first and then let me know what what happens.
You do it first and see if you find something weird happening.
Do you find any weird behaviour which is happening?
I'm shuffling this R A
but winter soldier is not,
you know, take constantly,
right? So if I check the last one,
right? Always. The last one is checked,
right?
In any case, And in any case, I'm shuffling right because there are only three.
So shuffle will be like pretty pretty bad,
right? Shuffle, shuffle scenario will be pretty bad.
But still,
uh, objects are not valid as the actual Children.
Uh, if you want to enter a collection,
uh, in this scenario, are you using this list
correctly?
Are you using the right starter code?
You know,
you can use the same code, which I am using. OK,
use the same
use the same exact code. OK, don't don't change it. Anything else?
Maybe something else is interfering
for other people. Can you see the,
um,
issue which is happening here? Right.
So if I start with a fresh
fresh fresh
with, like a
page
and once my dorm is ready, right, I'm clicking on the first one.
I'm clicking Shuffle R A.
It's shuffling the R a somehow,
but it is not changing
the check button, which should have changed. Technically,
does that make sense
or not?
The selected checkbox is staying on the same position, even if the element changes.
OK,
so this is a weird behaviour which is happening.
Was it expected
to happen or like, is it
some some error which is happening?
So
what? What I'm saying here is
if we restart, you know this this we
refresh this page.
What's happening here is I am using this shuffle function, right.
You don't have to worry about what it does.
What I tell you is it
is the R a elements. OK, so whatever a elements you pass in,
it will shuffle the R elements and then put it back to,
uh, the original state. Right?
So in this superhero state, I'm having starting with this data.
Right? And, uh, I have a button which would call these shuffle Super
A A.
And this logic basically will create a shuffled
A
right.
And we are changing the original superhero.
I mean, we are changing this superhero state right
inside this function as well.
Ok,
so we either, like, we are not changing the initial state. Right.
But we are changing the,
um,
uh, current state, which is there,
right? And this current state is being used
to,
uh, create a list of superheroes on the screen.
Right?
And we're passing the name of the superhero inside it.
The problem which is happening here is if I'm clicking on this one,
checkbox And if I'm clicking shuffle R A
it shuffles the R a somehow.
But
the checked element is still on the first one.
It's not moved
along with the other items which are there.
Does that make sense? Kavitha, what's happening? Do you understand this scenario?
What's happening? The problem which is happening? Yes.
Yes,
I understood that.
Yeah. Any other doubts?
Um, no.
Cool. Cool.
Cool.
Yes, I just repeated it.
Try to be a bit more,
uh,
to the class, OK? Confused.
Cool.
Uh,
at what part are you gonna choose
then? Basically, uh, but But they are part of the same,
um,
same component, right?
So they should technically be moved up and down.
Yes or no?
So all these three are different components altogether,
right?
I mean,
coming from the same component. But they are, like,
rendered separately on the,
um
on the dom. Right? So they are independent of each other technically,
but, uh, yes. What's happening here is
whenever I'm clicking this,
I suppose if I If I check this particular, uh, this first one, right,
So
so that if I'm checking and if I'm clicking the shuffle
A
So it is shuffling the
order of
the, um,
elements which are here.
Right?
But it is still keeping the check.
Like check the box as the first one. Only
does that make sense?
OK,
so this is the problem. It should not happen.
Actually, this is an unexpected behaviour,
OK?
And if you check
the console tab of de twos right?
There was something which the was telling us
a lot of times.
Don't don't worry about what this function does.
OK?
Don't worry about actually what this function
is doing this function is shuffling the
A
If I write the
dog for it,
right,
er this shuffles the superheroes
A
and
updates,
OK,
you don't have to worry about how it does it, right.
Just believe in the abstraction that it will shuffle the
A A and it will give you something.
OK,
One error, which I am seeing constantly here, right?
Is each child in the list should have a unique key crop.
Does that make sense
is unable to see this error, which is there?
Does everyone see this set?
So how we can resolve this is we can add a key here.
OK,
so to remove this kind of, uh, warning
there's a special
which is introduced when you are you know, um,
using map or something which is absolutely needed when you're using a map
is the key prop, OK? And this key prop should be something unique.
OK,
so superhero dot ID, for example, and in this scenario, OK,
so once you start putting this key prop right and you can use it as superhero dot ID
in here
and once you are done with this, and if you refresh the page again,
It will not give you that error anymore.
In the in the console Can you see that?
So this key prop is a special prop which react uses
to identify where the element was on the screen right where the element was on the do
So Now if I have the key prop And now if I try to shuffle,
my checkbox is moving along with it.
Can you see that?
Yes. Can everyone
see the same thing? See the same result?
Yes.
So this key prop basically tracks
right? I'll come come to it What it does.
So adding this key prop,
uh, as suggested right by by reactor
making the error go away
right
and you can set it to the elements ID value.
OK, so there's there's no more error.
But the thing is,
this React uses these keys to identify a specific list element and its state
OK,
so to keep track of the elements and their state, Right.
Uh, when when using a map kind of function or something like that.
Key prop is very essential, actually. Right.
So key prop there is There's a very detailed article on how key props actually work.
But for now, what you can understand is, um,
the act in its mind.
Uh,
when you're trying to map something, right,
it it wants to uniquely identify each of the elements
using something.
OK, so this is there should be something
to uniquely identify each of the dom elements so that it can keep track of its state.
Right? So we are setting that key to the whole component altogether,
OK, or whatever. You know, we are returning from the,
uh, JSX, right. We are setting the key prop to that. Suppose if,
for example,
there would be a Dev or something like that, right? So if there's a Dev
and here's a Dev again
OK,
so then, uh, the Dev would, uh,
like the Dev should have this key. OK,
so it goes to the outermost,
um JSX element is the parent JSX element here.
OK,
does that make sense
so that react can keep track of that
element, Which is there
OK, the whole whole thing, which is return from the map. It can keep track of it.
OK,
so if you have a Dev here right, if you have some other parent uh, element.
You put the key prop for the first,
uh, like the outermost parent which you're returning. Does that make sense?
OK, so this is the way you use keys and like, there's there's no,
uh,
and mention or something like that.
This is the actual syntax on how you would use keys.
OK?
Huh? Is it required only for eye travels? Mostly, it is used for eye travels.
There are two things I can still figure out how how they are working.
But since I travels are, you know, kind of, uh
things which are,
you know, which you are generalising right? Which you are bringing in from
a single element, which is which, Which should work work exactly the same,
right? What should be the differentiating factor in here?
So the differentiating factor,
uh, generally does not is not the prop, right?
Because prop values are again, you know, very subjective change subject to change
keys should be something which are not changing.
OK,
The key should be something which should be unique
in the Dom
tree.
Does that make sense? So there should be no colliding keys, so we can think of it as
kind of an, uh, ID element, which, which we were using earlier in normal JavaScript
right here when you you don't need an ID element, right? Uh, specifically.
And then we need an ID element to just pick up, uh,
the for for this pick up the element for the CS S
here. It's actually very essential to have a unique identifier,
like a key,
right,
which is a non changing thing, right,
Which is a non changing element that is very essential and important.
OK, I'll tell you what a non changing element and changing element would,
um, like cause an error fall.
OK,
so suppose, for example.
Suppose, for example, instead of the,
uh, ID, right,
I believe people know that you can also have the index in the map.
Do people know about it? Yes or no?
So if you use the index in here right, let's let's
use a single thing. Well, let's not use.
Let's not use this.
And
I hope people know about that. Your map function can have two arguments. One is the,
uh, item. And second is the index, yes or no?
Everyone, even if you don't know now, you know.
OK,
so that your map function. Whatever call back it takes takes in
it can take in two values. Uh, primarily which is one is the item itself.
And second is the index of that item.
OK? And then try to set the key as the index of that item, OK?
And then try to follow the behaviour again and see
if it works or not.
Does it work?
Or is it still back to the original letter?
Which which will bug which we are already having?
I only have this one, right? So I only have only have the single,
um
element, which I'm returning
Karachi.
Right? I removed that development actually,
OK, it was not needed for the time being. If you want, I can bring that back.
If if that's
something which does not confuse you I mean, I thought it might confuse people,
so I removed that for for for now.
Ok,
since I'm having only a single element which I'm
returning out of this map functions call back.
Right?
So I would definitely put the key in there only
Does that make sense? Rashi,
is there any doubt or confusion in this?
So I had like,
if there was any
There was something like that right
in here.
Then the key would be
a part of this.
OK,
if it is not there
and if you're returning just a single element,
then the key would be part of that single element too.
OK,
so with the the behaviour which I want you all to
observe is that if you are trying to put key as index
right, it is not giving the error.
But the bug is still there.
It's not giving us the warning anymore.
But the bug, which we were facing earlier, is still there.
Yes or no?
Is it there or no? Yes or no? Why you in?
Yes.
OK,
uh maybe
I have a doubt here.
So here. What will be the value of the that updated?
So which means that the set superheroes
So this one,
it could be anything, right? This could be any random area. So I suppose if you put in,
uh, Iron Man Black widow
sold
after this operation, right?
It is dynamic.
So that when when whenever we click the shuffle every time it keeps changing right,
it's not
Yes, it's because we are, you know, using it as a state right now.
Not not as a fixed data anymore,
right? So you are using this fixed data just to initialise this super
A
After that, everything is dependent on this function.
OK,
so that will. What will the state this function will determine about?
Does that make sense?
Yeah, because, I mean, yesterday you have showed an example of,
uh uh, that fixed state and it didn't change that hook
and the particular value didn't change. And it again, uh, went back. Right.
So for that, I'm asking this this value,
this particular value will be now become dynamic.
And when we start using multiple values
No, no, no. Don't get confused with that thing.
So yesterday was the example last time which I The example which I gave you
was something. Uh, let me put this out only. OK, let me not put it in
at all.
Maybe,
but I would just say initial data,
right. And I will initialise it with initial data.
So what is happening here is
in the last example what I gave you right yesterday or day before yesterday,
whenever we had session.
That example said that whenever you're calling a set state somewhere, right?
In any function or something,
this whole app function runs again.
Yeah,
but the value of superheroes does not,
uh, like remains the same, which was set using the set state.
OK,
so once the set state, uh, you know, set, like, created a new OK, let me create a
If we console, log
this area as well, right? It will
make sense a a copy.
So every time I am, uh, you know, creating let me refresh it.
So every time I click this button right, it will give me
three different elements, right?
Three different, uh, objects.
Whenever I click shuffle it will. It will create
three new objects, right?
Uh uh. From from the original one,
it will start,
you know, shuffling those accordingly.
Right?
So if it if it does,
actually let me see if it does or not.
Right? So once I'm creating that
right now Winter soldier and black widow,
Right? And then iron man. Right.
So it it updated the R a So it was first Winter Soldier, Iron Man Black widow.
But now it changed to winter soldier Blackwood,
so it just shuffled it somehow.
So the shuffle works the best when you are having,
uh, a lot of elements in it. So this this way of shuffling is very naive, actually.
And this logic is not very perfect to shuffle.
Um, this would be kind of biassed
not a true shuffle, but OK,
if you have a lot of elements the the the thing which we are aiming at here is to
shuffle the elements and then put the put that
shuffle la back into the state which was there,
right?
So whenever the fun like this set set function is called,
the whole app function will learn.
But the superheroes, uh, will stay the same, which which we try to set in from here.
Ok,
ok, that makes sense.
So that was something different than what you were doing yesterday
that that that example remains the same.
Ok,
ok,
does that make sense now or not?
So So don't worry about what this function actually does,
and the the the only thing which it does
is the state
and then
put it in there,
OK,
so because I mean you said this is not the
perfect way of the sorting out and the shuffling thing,
but you have used that method?
No, that 0.5.
So what other things can be used? Or you said that is not a perfect thing.
I mean, this is,
uh So there, there's a I'll tell after the decision.
If you stay, there's a whole debate about that.
Can, uh uh, like,
uh, computer systems truly generate random numbers or not?
Right.
So there's always a bias introducing randomness,
which is there in the computer system.
So So there are other, more complex ways of creating shuffle, shuffling, Right.
But this is one small way of doing it.
Uh, although this will work very not,
not not very well when there are a very small number of elements in there.
So if you if I increase the number of elements So as I increase the number of elements,
there will be more like things to select from right,
so
it will create more permutation combinations
that
that is a simple example. I
can
give you
so right now.
That's why sometimes if I'm shuffling right, so it's not, you know,
shuffling it Exactly,
because the shuffle value becomes the same as the original value.
Sometimes
number
of
combinations available.
OK,
that was the thing.
OK, one more question. Is it based on that number that 0.5 or,
uh,
what is the indication for that?
Uh,
random will give you something. So this is some other debate, right?
I I'll I'll get back to it. When? When the decision. Right.
We can discuss on this even more.
So this does not change the fact that the
OK,
how effective it? No, no, I'm very curious. Why?
That particular number can't be put one or one point by something like that.
That's why.
Yeah, you can use it. But again, because matter
random gives you,
uh, a number between zero and one, right.
And in this sort, you should either return a positive value or a negative value.
Right? So if you have a number less than 0.5 it will return a negative value.
If you have more than 0.5 right, it will return a positive value,
so that will determine where the element goes or not.
Right? So that that is something why we are using 0.5 because it's in the middle of it,
right?
Give us more like the best results which we can get if you put a 0.1
Actually biassed towards one side.
If you put 0.9 it will be biassed to the to the other side or something like that.
OK,
that is
they have to try it with a lot of a lot more combination and then I
have to get This is the best you can get actually with with matter if it
matter,
because it gives you like it's like a bell
coverage in the centre or something like that.
So I will not get into the detail of the math behind it,
but yeah, it is just shuffling the element.
OK,
Ok, thanks.
so,
Index,
though for now it would
be coming back to the discussion that you are having,
right?
Um, that just went to another interesting concept altogether of randomness and,
uh, and information theory and all that. Right,
But coming back to this list, right? So in the key.
Now, we are not getting the error anymore,
but still, the bug is remaining.
And the reason is
the reason is index is unique.
Uh,
but
like,
uh,
but the key as index right,
So what happens is
by default,
right index
is the key, which is set right to the to each of the elements so
react. What it does is if you do not specify this index prop,
uh, key prop. What it will do is it will set to identify the elements.
It will use their index only
OK,
but what happens is
when you shuffle that right,
so the index also changes.
Does that make sense?
So if you are shuffling the R A and you're changing the original array also,
so the index of that particular element is also changing.
Does that make sense now?
So So suppose uh, Winter soldier was an index zero right
now when we shuffled the index, Winter Soldier is on now Index something else,
but
the act saw that. OK, you check
the index zero only.
OK, so it's still checking the index zero always. Right. So it is checking.
OK, which index is checked?
So suppose if I check index zero
always index zero will be checked, right? So the act cannot figure out,
uh,
if the you know,
uh, because index has not changed right for that check box index is still zero,
right?
So if you use something unique which, which from which we can identify,
then react will match it with that unique value right,
which is not changing right now. Index is changing, right? Always.
Whenever I'm shuffling
the index of the R a elements is changing,
so react cannot,
you know, it gets confused and cannot figure out if if if it has to update,
uh, which value it has to update. So it keeps it,
you know that so index is unique,
but
with key index
key assigned to the to an element changes on every shepherd. Right.
So we should aim to keep keys which are unique and non changing,
which are constant kind of things.
So we so I
can make a direct equality comparison
to see if the key has changed or not, right?
Or to see if the element has moved or not right in the dome or not something like that,
right? This is why the first element was checked. Always, even if we try to shuffle.
So if I try to remove the confusion What? What? What? What? What's happening here is,
uh, let me
somehow
if I can
Hm?
Can I pass in the index in here as Well,
uh, ID X
AD X equal to index. Something like that. Right.
Uh,
Christian, what are you trying to get at?
Let me let me try an example. So what I'm doing here is,
uh, Now I'll also take in the index as a prop and see if that
thing changes or not.
OK,
so Index along with it.
OK, just show the index along with it.
Let me
it and see if it
comes up.
Hm?
Why can I not see the index here?
I don't know what
the problem is.
Is that OK? Oh, it is IBX
AD X.
I DS
OK. Now let's see if
explanation checks out,
OK?
And let me put put something, uh,
put
it like that.
OK, so for now, I have 01 and two. If I
put in the
can. You see, the index is not changing.
So the index, which I am trying to put in there, right,
So the index of the list element is not changing when I'm, you know,
updating that thing
right? Hence it's always check that same index.
Right?
But if I try to pass in the key, as you know,
um,
superhero dot ID
right?
Then
what will happen is then what will happen is if I refresh this page
if I check this
and now what I can see is
it is moving like the index is still not changing. But now reactor is checking with
the
index. Uh, like with the key prop, actually. Right. So it's not,
uh, using the key prop as index anymore, right? Does that make sense? Does that make
the scenario even clear or not,
or does it still confuse you?
So what's happening here is the index basically
does not make any sense to use as a unique key.
OK, because it's changing always
right. So it's not unique anymore to a particular element.
OK,
so hence we should try to use a unique key which is a non changing one.
so that I can pick up the changes and move along with it.
OK,
so we should avoid using avoid index as key in other scenarios as well. 100%? Yes.
You should always avoid index, uh, to be used as a key.
It will give you a lot of unwanted errors which you would not expect.
Uh, since the check is set
to use state does react bind both ID and state when it was state
so react basically, uh, would, you know,
see if the component has moved or not, Right
So it it's it's binding kind of. I would say this like it's hooking
the state
to the key prop, which is there,
right?
So to identify which,
uh, state uh, which element should I, you know, go into and change the value of
Does that make sense?
So you can you can you can imagine it as, like, reactors hooking.
They stay with the key.
Which is there.
OK,
does that make sense to everyone or not?
Index is set for every element. Yes, every element will have an index for sure.
Right
and key. Basically, what you do is key.
Uh, is something which you use
to uniquely identify
each of the
dom elements.
OK,
so this is something which you can use to directly pick up
the dorm element like I can use to pick up that or,
you know,
um, keep track of that dorm element.
If it If if if some suppose, for example, right.
If if If I take an example, if three people live in three different houses, right?
And if I ask them, you know,
or or or three people are standing in three different boxes.
And if I asked them
to you know, uh, shuffle this, uh, shuffle their value in the boxes, right?
And if they take the boxes along with them, like, I cannot
make any change like, make make any difference, right?
So it's all the same to me
for for like, if I am the
if I'm having three different boxes in there,
right,
it will all look the same to me, right? So the order does not
order Order. I cannot maintain the
order in there.
So that is 11 problem, which is the which should exist with keys and I DS and all that,
right?
So to simplify the concept for you all not to confuse you all at all,
I'll try to recap it,
keep keep an eye on the screen.
One thing which react did was
once we started using map,
it wanted to have something to uniquely identify every element
which is returned to the map.
OK, one
second.
We cannot use something which is changing altogether, right,
which is changing constantly to uniquely identify a particular thing.
Right
Index is some one thing, which is you constantly changing.
Hence we cannot use it to identify
the change. Right
key is like like there is like, this is the point where key comes in,
right?
And the key should be something which is non changing and unique
for each of the elements. Right?
So that we can like a react,
can pick up the change and update the dom
accordingly and does not give you unintended bugs.
Do these four points make sense to everyone?
Yes or no?
So this is a very this would become very common,
um, interview question.
Also, if your interviewer wants to drill you after 1.5 hours or something, right,
So it goes if you want. If you if they want to go in deep
right into JavaScript or into react knowledge,
then they might ask you this question and you might
get, you know, take on that. So, in that scenario, you would say that
uh, key is used
to uniquely identify the dom elements by react
OK,
And we cannot use anything in the key
right, which, uh,
is changing
or it is not unique.
OK,
so
all key should be unique and so and something
and a value, which is non changing. So so sorry, I can
I about it. Ok, I, I try to put that in the side as well. I'll put it in the notes
so that,
like me,
put down
comment for this.
He
should be unique
and should be non changing.
React uses keys
to identify
the elements
returned from the map
two
update
the
sea.
Oh,
you
keep
track of them
during
three
renders.
Ok, so added this here in the notes. Right.
So you can when you when you're going through the slides,
you can have a look at it as well.
Ok, cool.
OK,
so the takeaways from here? Uh,
yeah, and and definitely they would have explained it. So
the reason, um I mean
the stress about about it so much is the same. Right? So
you want to react to understand what you are
trying to change and not just change randomly.
Right? So the takeaways here is a list and react is an area of J six elements,
right? Something like this
added
a
map method can be used to render a list
in a simpler format.
Each
of the list elements are set to be set to a unique key crop
unique
amongst sibling list elements. OK, not the entire.
You don't need to worry about the entire term element for now.
OK,
so you you need to have unique.
Um,
actually, this works for entire dome as well.
We'll have to see.
OK, I think this works for the entire dome. I'll I'll I'll get this checked as well.
OK,
we should always have the name
like so
Ask the question that,
uh, like key. Should we always name the element
as list?
No, it's not.
It's not necessary,
right? So let's add multiple list elements in there
and let's see,
right if you refresh
right,
So one thing which comes in here is
you don't need to worry about,
you know, you don't need to
worry about basically
the
you don't need to worry about, uh the key for, you know,
to be unique throughout your dorm.
It just only needs to be unique for the,
uh,
you know, siblings of that particular thing.
OK, and there's no hard and fast to to name it list or something like that.
But the key prop is
something which is unique.
OK,
by default key set to the R a index
and the assumption here for, you know,
reactors that the order of elements does not change, right?
That's why it puts it as the index.
And, uh, if if, if somehow the order of index,
this is something which you will need Only when the order of these,
um siblings might change right or the order of this list elements might change.
In that scenario, you only need,
um you know that the the key becomes very critical and crucial
else What? What react does Is it by default Sets it to index
and even if you set it to index, you might not face any problems.
Uh, till your list is not shuffling or changing or something like that.
But it's always better
to use a unique key
which is always, you know, you know, not changing and fixed
OK.
Or at least unique amongst the element of the of the of the,
um
uh of the the the list elements which are there. Ok,
if the list element
can change order, use another unique key to specify each element.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Keys and lists clear to people. So there were only these takeaways.
If you all are good, let's proceed to side effects. Right.
So these are some,
uh, interview questions I've put in. You can go through them.
OK,
let's then get to side effects with books. Everyone ready?
100%. It is a good practise to have I DS and objects
there are also, you know, cute ways. Good ways to
create unique is always right.
Um,
you might search them on the internet. It it gives us some good math,
right?
But it's a very elegant, small,
small one liner code which could help you generate unique keys.
All right, that is something also that you can do.
But if you do not have any, um,
ID prop along with your object,
OK?
Goods?
Yeah, You ID is one thing, and and one thing is, what you can do is
you can create
a uniquely identified I DS,
um, in C two also right. So during when you are creating this,
uh, list there, also, you can write some Js expression to create
that, uh, unique ID as well. So that is something for advance use cases.
If you get to it,
OK, when you get to it, you'll you'll understand.
OK,
so performing side effects right
side effects first for one.
If I start with side effects,
right will be dealt with this word when you are doing functional programming
with people who are new
side effects are operations which can
affect other components
and cannot be done during the rendering process
or basically,
side effects can be anything which are not related to rendering it down.
OK, a simple definition would be this
OK. Side effect could be anything
which is not related with rending the dom.
So, for example, fetching data from the API calls
or manually changing the Dom right?
Like the page title or something like that, if you're changing it
or
in In that scenario, what you can use is something called as a
use effect
right for side effects.
Does that make sense?
Does that make sense? What side effects are
OK?
So type two types of side effects. Two types of effects are there.
One is which need clean up,
right?
Like suppose, uh,
don't which don't need clean up like suppose API calls or manual dorm dates.
Or maybe if you console logging, that's also a side effect, actually.
Right. If you console logging some value of the state,
that's also a side effect,
which you are performing
right, because it is something which is not pertaining to entering the dorm,
right? It it's pertaining to something else. Right?
Console Logging is something else, right?
It does not,
um,
um
affect the dome
directly.
OK,
It needs
and other type of effects are something which needs cleanup, like clearing timers,
which was started.
Uh, do you remember any place where we did this? Some did something like this
where we, uh, removed the timers, Uh,
from the component.
Any place? Do you remember
Unmount, right?
How many? How many of you will remember that? Actually,
Component
Which one
component and mount component and mount. Right.
So when you are doing this stock data example, at that point of time,
we did a component Will and mount.
Um,
kind of,
uh um
life cycle method. And then there we used to clear up the timers. Right.
That was kind of a side effect,
which was which we we were performing using the browser API S which are there, right?
Like set like set, interval set, time out and all that stuff.
OK,
so let's start with side effects which do not need any cleanup. OK,
the effects
which have access
to
comp like effects, have access to competence, props and state. Right.
And you can write a user textbook. Let's let's start with an example. OK,
let's start with an example.
Should I start with this? Only
let me start with this example.
Uh, I can hide this up casually. You don't need it.
Oh,
what just brings in all these spaces and I don't like it at all.
Ok,
ok, let me open it in a new window
eight
and also bringing up the console
and, uh, also create a console dot log.
Um
Updated,
Ok?
Hm.
And let me also add another input. OK,
let me let me add another
input.
Uh, just to make it interesting.
Ok,
let's start with something and then we'll add
the
to make it much more interesting and see different use cases of it. OK,
so for now what I have done, I believe I understand what this example means.
What it example is trying to do.
So it has a account, a set count, a handle count function which is setting the account
right for whatever input which I'm having in here.
OK,
so if I try to update this,
you can see the updated count as being,
you know, the the this account is being updated. Can you see that?
I clear this.
If I update it, date on each of the
render which is there, right? This updated is being triggered.
Can you see that?
And also
our
like you can have a look at this title, you know, document title as well.
Ok,
so if I'm trying to update this,
it's also updating the document title also because
I am here and I'm setting document the title
to count and the count value, which is there,
and user effect always has the access to the latest,
uh, state value, right?
So similar to something like confident
data amount and component data update.
Right? So competent data update. Always had the CM,
um always had the latest value of the props, right?
Or or or already had the, you know, at least last value previous value of the props
here because we are using hooks.
We're always getting the latest value of the count prop.
OK, so once when I'm updating this, I'm getting the latest value of the count.
Meanwhile, this
you know, each each render which is happening is triggering this update.
Does that make sense to everyone?
To use effect is
the the The syntax is something like this. You like to use effect
directly.
You don't need to, you know, assign it to something else or something like that,
and directly you just, like, pass in a callback function
and perform any side effect inside this callback function if you want.
OK, so this can be fetching like a P data or something like that.
You can do all of that inside it.
By default, huge effect will run
for initial renders and all
renders. So basically it's a combined version
of competent dead mount and component data update. Does that make sense
or not?
So if I refresh this page, it will automatically be run at least two times
once the component for the first enter.
And so once I this is the component data amount
version of it. So it it as soon as the component is mounted,
it ran.
Once I update it, it will run again.
OK,
so every time I keep updating it, it will start, You know, uh, printing it always.
OK, so it's kind of a
combined version of component
data amount
right? And component data update. Does that make sense?
So it's it's it simplifies a code from two life cycle methods to a single hook.
OK,
so what you can do is you can create a new component for now, OK,
and call it use effect. No cleanup dot Js
with a given starter code. I'll give you the starter code
for that.
Let me create it also. So let me create a new,
uh, session five I'll create
you would affect
no clean up,
Gorgeous.
I have the starter code. I'll give it to you.
OK,
so this is a starter code.
Got it, And I'll give it to you.
Create a new file in, uh, section five,
right? And name it, you know, use effect. No cleanup or UV. No clean up. Whatever.
Right? Whatever. Whatever you
like.
OK.
And for a
dot Js, this will be your starter code. OK, I'll give you the starter code code
dot JSL
Once you're done with the,
uh this particular component,
just let me know and I'll give you the starter code for 0.0.
So this
some support for R dot DS as well?
Mhm
I
Yes,
OK, I
misspelt it
And here I have to
not use this.
OK,
once you are done,
then you can use this app dot
Js starter code as well.
Ok,
so use this in your app dot Js
and please update the value of, you know, use no effect clean up whatever
once they're done plus one in the chart.
So in the
US effect, no cleanup component, you'll need to do some things.
Once you're done, just let me know.
I'll give you 30 more seconds to get your starter code ready,
OK,
Two more people at least should do it so that I can move ahead of this.
so fetch the user data right and load the email
value by calling the update email on all renders.
Does that make sense?
So you need to fetch the user data and log the email value by calling update email
on
all renders.
I hope you understand how you would be able to do it.
It's fairly direct. I believe
so. This update
update email is already logging the data. OK,
it's already a logging the it's already getting the update email,
and it's already logging the email.
You just need to find a way to,
you know, trigger this function on all renders of this component.
Once you're done, just share the code which helped you achieve that.
One thing which I would tell you
is you do not need a synch and
a weight inside a bit.
Um, you know,
uh,
you don't need to make the callback function a sync right? You don't need to make
the US
effect callback function asynchronous.
OK,
there would be a few caveats for this one as well.
If anyone of you at least does it, I'll
be happy to
explain the solution
because this can be a bit tricky.
OK,
mhm
other people,
anyone else who has done it
or else what, error or what warning or anything.
If you are facing the threat, you know,
and try it out also
what
except
a
I am at least expecting a few more answers.
OK,
we
need to close this use effect also. OK,
so what we want to do is since the question asks us
to update the value on all renders
what is something which what is some hook which is called on all renders,
which is
us effect.
Yes or no?
This is something we just discovered discussed, right?
The use effect is something which will be executed on all
renders.
Right.
So what we can do is we can just call and use effect.
And inside this use effect, we can call the update image.
OK,
so once we are done with this
So once we are
done with this particular
scenario,
not sure why it's still called it.
But anyways, so first time, first time it was rendered, it showed us the email.
If I render it again
right,
it shows me the email. If I render it again, it updates the email,
email, email, email, email, email, email, email. So it's making
the, you know, call on each render, right. So every time this is rendering,
it is showing fetching the email in getting back, getting it back to me.
And the way I know it is because it will keep on making the
network requests like this. Can you see that?
So it will start making all the network requests again and again.
Like how many? How many network requests we have already made,
right.
If I keep making these changes, it's starting to make all these network requests.
Can you see that?
So all these network requests are made because I regard a re
render.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Does the solution make sense to everyone or not?
What happened?
So on. So this is something which you achieved.
So on every vendor we are fetching the email and getting the value
right. And I can see, uh, that I'm making the calls because I can do that in my
no
I. I can see that those those calls in my,
um,
network
tables OK, somewhere here. I made some few more calls to here. They are.
OK,
what
can you check that if they are being made on
each message Change and user ID change also,
Can you Can you check that?
Can you check that if they are being made on,
um
you know, message changes as well as user ID changes,
are they?
If I change the user? ID, will this will this function be called again?
Can you see that?
If I'm changing this user email right
now, I'm getting the
new user email for each of the user. ID does that make sense?
So if I'm creating, like for for 13, I don't have anything, right?
Uh, that would give me an error, but till 10. I till 12. I have something. Right?
So what I want is what What I essentially wanted
was to achieve something where I would update the, uh, user ID,
right? And I get the email of that person,
right? That would be a better use case, right?
Yes or no.
So but But right now,
what's happening here is if I even if I change the
message or if I change the user ID right here now,
right now, I'm like, fetching the unnecessary data right again and again.
Always. Does that make sense to you or not?
Everyone,
I hope I'm not rushing with this.
I'm not very fast while working with it.
If you feel I'm going very fast, just just ask me to slow down, OK,
so for now, what's happening here is I want actually to If if I click on this
right,
it should bring me the new user email.
But
this is unnecessary, right? This is a necessary email.
This is unnecessary request, which I'm making
right. I'm again and again, like calling
the same function
because it was the part of it, right? It's It's It's like trying to update
it always,
right? It should not be the case
at least.
OK,
Because I'm passing the user ID and the message both right.
I only want
when the user ID changes, right? It should,
uh, make a call when it does not change. It should not make a call.
How would you do it in normal class companies, Can you remember?
Can anyone tell me, How would you do it in normal class component?
How would you check
if, uh,
the
like when to make the call or when not to make the call? Because
II, I remember that in compered
update. We always used to,
uh,
have a check. Right?
So that chick,
can anyone tell me what that check would have been?
Right, Right.
We would check that if the user ID has
changed in order at least so like something like,
uh, if,
um this dot props is, uh, pro this dot props dot ID
is not equal to equal to props dot ID Something like that, right?
Or previous props dot ID then only make the call. Does that make sense
or not?
So we used to check it inside the
data. The data date, right? Always
are people with me or not.
So
Kavita
Dana
Vikash
my
Sunil.
Ah,
yes.
So we only need to make the API calls on the user ID change. Right?
So we can you know, Actually,
you know something like something like this we used to do right.
So previous
user ID
not equal to
this
Do ID then only make the like then only call this this Do update email.
Yes, everyone can relate to this
yes or no?
Yes,
if,
um
so if you want to do that same thing
with the hooks version, right?
There's something which we can pass in,
um
along with this use effect which is called as a dependency of that use effect. Right?
So this dependency there's an area of dependencies that you can pass right,
which would basically tell us effect on
what to listen to, right? What changes to listen to
and at what time you want to make the
call.
Ok, at what time you want to run this,
um effect. OK, so here you can pass in a dependency R. And
you can say that. Ok,
uh, props dot User
ID
OK, this is something that you are getting.
So
whenever I'm changing the user ID only at that point of time,
try to make a call else. Please don't make it,
OK,
so now you use the fact to listen to this brow
user ID.
And whenever this project user ID is changing
right only at that point of time it will make a call. Ok, so here I am making a call.
Can you see that
here? I'm making the call. I'm changing the user ID
But if I don't change the user ID,
there is no call being made. Can you see? No call is being made here.
Does that make sense to everyone or not?
So the renders are there.
But the call is not being made unless and until I change the
user ID
does that make sense?
So this is very simple version of, you know, working with, uh
uh, checks and dependency so we can make, uh, user effect.
Listen to some some of these, uh, values, right?
And see if those values change, then only
call this function else. Do not run this function.
Does that make sense?
So the this this R a is called as a dependency R A.
You can pass in any number of dependencies in here,
right?
So if you remove this, uh, user ID
and you only pass, uh, maybe
pros dot MS team, which is message,
right?
Then
it will render on message,
right? But it will not run on user ID change. Can you see that?
So if even if I am changing the user ID, it is not making any calls,
which is something which I don't want.
But still, I'm just telling you that it will now only run.
It will now only run when the message is changing.
Does that make sense?
Uh, why was it written inside square brackets here?
This is an array, right?
So this is an array which you are passing.
So so use effect. Something looks something like this.
So use effect,
right
and inside is the first argument is a function
right? Second argument is an array.
OK, this is how the US effect looks like.
So the first thing is a callback function.
OK, callback
function.
And the second thing is the dependency.
Got it.
OK,
got it. This is how it looks like.
Makes sense to do one.
Now, if you try this out, then see what what happens?
Can anyone tell what would happen if you try this out?
Go ahead and, uh, you know, add a dependency. I do not add any dependency to it.
See what happens then Can you Can you tell the behaviour of
what What it would do?
It will render only once something like
which which, uh
component Uh you know,
method would you You would relate it to
So it will only render once once the component is mounting.
Right?
So
it works exactly similar to component amount.
Right?
So if you are you know, not adding anything in here as a dependency R a
Then what will happen is it will only run on the
it will only run on mounting Ok, Once this element is mounted, it is
the change
now. No changes make any difference to it.
Does that make sense?
So this is the version of component Denmark.
OK,
does that make sense to everyone?
Got it.
So
So you should not directly relate to it because the concept is very different
of hooks and, like, cycle methods.
But there is something to just, you know, connect the dots together,
right? So that we are like, it's a new way of writing a new way of implementing things.
But, uh, you can still make the things which they still use the,
uh,
you know, kind of ideology, which you are trying to use in competent, uh,
life cycle methods.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Yes or no?
So it's working similar to component dead.
Everyone understood
what the dependency R is and why we need it.
So, dependency R a helps us. Uh, you know, make the,
um,
use effect, uh, work as competent update.
Right.
If we do not add any dependencies in the
dependency it is, it is working similar to component data amount.
Right.
And now what is left? What is one thing which is left
in the three golden,
uh, life cycle methods
so we did comprehended amount. We did comprehended update
and what is left now
One thing which is left is
component.
Will Unmount?
Yes.
So that is something which is we will
understand
when you're working with
OK,
so let me
bring up the example.
Ok,
let me bring up the example
So component will Unmount uh was used to clean
up resources on a component and mount right?
So with use effect
you if you return a function with some cleanup logic like
like something like this. Or maybe if you clear a timer or something like that right
then
it will act like component Will unmount OK
or it will,
um I should not actually say this, but
I mean,
we can for now work with this particular thing.
OK, let me add drop dot user ID.
Right,
So this function basically will be run
before the component is unmounted
Does that make sense
or before Basically this effect is un mounting.
I would say
that would be a better way to,
uh, state it
so because we can have multiple use effects as well.
Like we used to have multiple, uh, use states.
Right.
So in that scenario when this effect is basically un mounting right,
which will be the time when the component is un mounting.
Right. This function will be run immediately before the
component is and mounting.
Does that make sense?
So this is
executed
just before
D use effect.
It is un mounting
or
or technically,
when the
Popo
is unmarked.
OK,
so that is the only time when the use effect will be, you know, removed
or or the use effect listeners or whatever will be removed. At that point,
you would want to run this function,
OK?
Does that make sense to everyone?
I'll give you an example. I'll bring up an example right
here. You want to only make this particular change.
But in the app dot
You make a few changes
the app dot Js
Let me bring up a few changes.
One is I don't need to export this.
The other is I would
Hi This up.
Right.
Bring this import
down here where I need it,
ok,
and remove all these spaces which are very annoying.
Please bear with me for one second
hm
control
Oh, thank God. Thanks a lot. So
you you save the day
OK,
so control basically removes all the spaces. Thanks a lot.
Uh, now I'm gonna use it heavily.
Use effect
with cleanup,
but yes.
Right.
And here I will have
all these things which I had already had
control. Less
smooth, smooth as whiskey.
Very nice
control, X.
And I'll update control V.
OK,
I believe the example would now be ready,
and I'll have to just call this.
You will affect
with no cleanup.
Oops.
Use effect
with cleanup
and
repent.
Cool.
So now I have this example ready for me,
right? And in this example, you can see with clean up what I did.
I just have this cleanup logic written in here. Nothing is gonna actually, you know,
um,
directly working.
But,
um I mean, we are not cleaning up technically anything,
but we just want to see when it is done, actually.
OK,
so if I try to, you know, just update the message and update this something,
uh,
when I when I'm clicking on show component, right,
then it is, you know, trying to update the state, right?
Whatever. Whenever this function,
can you can you see whenever. Whenever this use effect is basically, uh
you know, finished at that point of time, it is running up the cleanup logic,
so I could, you know, rephrase this and say,
uh, whenever this use effect,
uh, function has executed,
this
is before
executed.
Um,
when
the
function
ends, or whatever, like finishes executing
you would only need these kind of, uh, you know, um,
effects
only when you are. You know,
uh, trying to,
uh, clean up some
but, uh, time or something like that. Only in that scenario, as you will be,
uh, working.
So it technically is not exactly equal to competent, Val,
and mount
the reason
the reason is competent Val amount runs only before
the competent and mounting right,
but use effect. Uh, because it's like a normal callback function.
It will always, you know, try to run this particular thing.
You can make it technically run like you competent data and mount. But
that is a villain mount.
But that is for some different, you know,
through some different logic.
OK, so you can have a a altogether separate use effect for it,
right? And then you can only return this function.
Does that make sense? If I summarise what I wanted to do with this particular thing
is
that
we have component data and mount here.
We have component,
uh, data update here,
but we do not have a direct equivalent of component will and mount in
books, OK?
Because
we can do cleanup effects,
but
these cleanup effects are run.
Uh, as soon as you you know, for
render like for whenever your function renders
right, because each of the time what you have,
what what you're doing is you are actually rerunning this whole app.
Does that make sense?
So
in in that scenario,
you cannot actually figure out when your computer is
un mounting and when your computer is mounting,
right, because on every render your whole app is running,
does that make sense to you or not?
So there's no technical concept of mounting or un mounting anymore.
Which is there, right?
That's why we we should avoid using these words like comprehended mount
and mount, or all that stuff,
because there's no concept of mounting and mounting anymore, which is left, right,
So
but But you can say that
we can try to mimic the effect of those life cycle methods
using use effect hook
does that make sense? So technically, if someone asks you that,
are they equivalent? You would say that you should say directly. No.
And that would spark a very intriguing conversation with your interviewer as well.
OK, and then you can explain that because, you know,
we render the whole app is being run
like whole app is being rendered again and again.
Uh, the concept of directly mounting or un mounting, I would say, does not,
uh, directly translate from classes to functions.
OK, hence we cannot just say directly that they are,
um, an equivalent of,
um,
life cycle methods.
But they are something which are hooks and they retain the value, or or, you know, uh,
help us to perform side effects.
Uh, on the go. Like when? When? When? Whenever the Whenever they end.
That is happening or whatever Like that.
Does that make sense to everyone or not?
So as effects run for every render use effect, returning function,
right?
Um, it's technically not,
you know, equal to
the component.
Will unmount
Does that make sense?
So you can think of it something like this You can think of us effect as comped
mounted or data amount.
But technically,
you know now how they work, right?
So you know how the render works and all that Does that make sense to everyone?
So you know how the render works. And you also know that
you know, your clean up logic will be called on every render
right? If your component is you know, you you're showing the component or whatever,
right?
This is
not a very good example of
having this. You should technically show the component,
but yeah, OK. I mean, for for now it works,
right?
Uh, I should say
allow
of this.
Whatever.
And this would be a better way of
saying
so once you are,
you know, allowing updates
and that point of time.
Every time you are trying to run the logic, you are running the cleanup logic as well.
Ok,
does that make sense, people,
And when you are, you know, in any case, when you are, you know,
removing that component right At that point of time also,
you're
you are reentering the
parent.
Hence you are running this once more.
Does that make sense or not? Everyone
is is un mounting kind of concept clear.
I mean, there's no concept of on mounting and mounting,
but is the cleanup effects clear or not? A better way of writing?
This is generally something like this, right? So you might find,
uh, this kind of syntax Pretty pretty common in
a lot of cleanup effects. Example,
OK.
Or even this
right? Even this is very common,
right?
But you you might not find function like people writing function.
They will write something like this.
OK,
does that make sense to everyone?
Any confusions?
Any doubts you can ask me right now because they're about to do an activity.
Ok,
OK, we're about to do an activity. Any doubt you can ask me,
right? I'll give you your starter code.
Oh,
God. It's a very big
pardon.
So I'll have a starter code on the
dot.
OK,
so this is a whole starter code
and I hope you can understand what this code does and what the sport means,
right?
Because now we're going to convert.
Oh God. I cannot copy it directly.
Can like, can you all get the code from here
directly
from this file?
Will you be able to do that?
OK,
OK, OK, ok.
And in your app dot Js You only need to have,
uh you know, you don't need all this.
You only need to have
your dog picks component on me.
I had it somewhere.
Mm mm.
Mhm.
So in your app dot Js you would need something like this only.
Right?
So what we have here is basically
is is basically, uh,
a class component.
The thing we wish you want to do here with this last component is
kind of convert it to a functional component. I hope people can do that.
Will you be able to do it?
Will you be able to convert it to a functional component and also hope you can get the
values from here?
So write the hooks equivalent of the given code
with session for dog picks with hooks dot Js.
Right. You can create a new file so that you don't
miss the
one
right.
And this, which displays a random dog image on load.
And, uh, if you have selected the breed, then it should also, you know,
use the breed so you can use all the same logic which are written in here.
But instead, this writer hooks version of it,
OK,
or what we can do is wait on this activity.
OK, let me discuss one thing with with you, and then we can come back to this activity.
Does that make sense?
Will that will you all be fine with that?
So we have to, you know, address one issue which we are
hanging behind.
So, one thing, uh, with when we were when we switched from classes to functions,
was classes are too complex to understand,
right?
And the second thing which we the issue,
which we had hold on that activity for Now we'll do it, Uh, just after two minutes.
Once we complete this issue, which is there?
Ok,
so the logic was spread across different life cycle methods when we were, you know,
using
the,
um
Then we were using the,
uh,
life cycle methods.
But now, with hooks, it is much more elegant and simpler. Can you see that?
Yes. Plus one, if you agree
on all this
right.
So now you can grow code by functionality, right? And not
just by, you know, uh, splitting it across a
component data, amount of
amount and all that right.
So
So you. You you You're splitting. Saves your time. Right?
So that is something which helps,
right?
Another thing is, uh, you know, this this was one of the major issues.
The second major issues,
One was the classes can be confusing and a lot of boilerplate code.
Second was logic was spread across different life cycle methods.
OK, so we have already discussed the first issue earlier,
right?
And now we when we when we are using new state and all that
and with the second, uh, use effect,
we tackled the issue of logic being spread across different life cycle methods.
Third thing is, we cannot reuse logic without JSX easily
right will not get into this much in detail. Right.
But this is something that you will gradually learn
when you start becoming comfortable with.
OK,
so they decide. Like if I if I, you know, run like go with takeaway for hooks is
by default,
Use effect, transformation
and all renders
we can skip
effects. Uh, you know, we can skip the calling of that use effect, uh, call back
if we pass in a second argument, which is an
a where we can specify
what changes to listen to
right
and
the return function of use effect can be used for cleanup actions for that effect.
Does that make sense
an art?
So for that effect, if you are having something
you can clean up that, um, effects, uh, you know, AAA any any,
any clean the actions you can do inside for that effect inside that effect only.
And you don't need to split the logic again
into something else,
OK,
and now we'll come back to that activity. I hope if if this makes sense to everyone,
then I believe once you are, uh, completed,
once you complete that activity from converting that class
component to a functional component,
then you will probably be very comfortable with understanding
hooks and how they work and all that stuff.
Is it clear to you or not this takeaways or not? This is this takeaways which you had
for side effects with folks.
I want to answer for everyone who is there and if there's any doubt,
you can definitely go ahead and ask, and then we'll start doing the activity.
OK,
we have.
So you're my
deep
sun. Everyone clear. Prachi
clear
Sua
Neha
pul
Taron Kal
Rashan
Raviraj.
Ah,
Yash Kuna
Mohe.
Ok,
everyone is clear on this, right?
I hope. Cool.
So let's start with this. Let's do this activity then.
OK?
So I hope
you can see this code. So this code has a class dog picks, right?
Create basically a new,
uh, dog picks.
Uh, dog pick
books dot Js
and then try to write a code in here. OK, don't try to mess up with the original code.
It will
cause more problems than good.
OK,
so we have a constructor
where we have this do default breed set as something
OK,
we have this dot state set as something
which is breed and you know this dot default breed whatever and we have an image link
as well.
We have a competed amount now I believe you
know where where the logic inside this will go.
We have a comprehended update where I believe again. You know what? What?
What are we checking for which will go
inside
What part of that hook
which you which you will use, right?
And then we have this render dog image function right, which you can use directly
with some minor changes like you know where
where you're setting the state and all that.
And then we have a handle.
Breed change where again, you have to set the state in the newer fashion.
And here,
inside this you will only change the places where
you are using this keyword and all that.
OK,
does that make sense to everyone or not
so quickly? Um, you know,
try to write a
hooks, Fun hooks version of this function,
uh, hooks version of this class,
and I'll wait for you.
Right? Uh, for the next 45 minutes,
and then we will, you know, see the solution of it quickly,
and then we'll close up this session.
OK,
So this is the last activity for today
as well as
Yeah, for for us.
OK,
everyone understood the assignment.
What do you have to do
but it
proceed.
OK, I'll, I'll wait for any doubts if you have.
Right.
And, uh, I'll also, you know, be present
with you throughout for this,
right?
And once you're done, we'll discuss the solution.
Mhm.
Once you're done, basically paste the
four sandbox link so that I can see
Yeah.
Are you all able to do it? Or is there any blocker which you're facing?
You
the
You are able to understand what you want to do here.
Be aware of the keyboard This and, uh,
you know,
that is the only thing that you need to be careful of. The rest of the things just go
inside the hoax
that it can be
maintaining it. Using the hooks.
You start doing it bit by bit,
people.
You open it on the side,
you start doing it when
I
Ok,
quickly, quickly. Eyes on the screen
if you're able to do it.
Um,
well, enough if you are if you're if you're not able to do it,
If you're still still trying,
have a look on the screen and then you can try it again.
You know,
um, once you
visited the slide.
OK,
Do I have people on on the screen with me?
Yes or no.
Quickly, quickly.
So first thing which I want to do here
is
just a second.
The sides
they can see what
what they exactly wanted
need to do.
Um
OK,
so I have to bring in
the breed and all that. Ok,
cool. So what I can do is I can write a function which I can say dot
uh, with books or whatever right? I can say Say something like that I believe. Yes.
I hope people agree on this.
OK,
And here what I can do is I can start with whatever is inside the constructor.
I can use it as a set state.
So whatever the breed, I can have set a breed
right?
And I can start with the use state
and the breed is random.
OK,
so my default value just went to
random here.
Ok,
The other thing, which I can keep in here, is the image link.
Right?
Or set image link.
Something like that new state,
which is plan.
Does that make sense to everyone or not?
So you have basically converted this constructor
into these two
books to maintain this state plus one. If you understand this patch,
yes,
The next thing is, whatever the render logic is inside it,
I would want to have it inside my
return.
Ok,
so whatever the render logic is here with me,
I would want it in my return directly.
OK, The next next thing which I do
where I have this dot state I will just go ahead and remove it. I don't need it at all
right.
And whenever I Whenever I have a this basically I'll just go ahead and remove that.
OK,
so
and the value I can also let me OK, bring in
default breed which is random,
right? And let me set the state as default breed
Ok,
so my other things are not breaking
ok,
this dot state is gone This dot dot This is gone
ok
anywhere else if I'm using this,
OK, this dot
render dog image is also gone
and I'm not using this anymore,
ok,
Does this make sense to everyone or not
what we are just trying to do here?
OK, so my render logic is done plus two in the chart if you understand
OK,
the next thing is to bring in these two functions into the scene.
OK, so when I bring in these two functions in the scene,
I first need to add constant in front of it both.
Second thing is, instead of this dot set set,
I'll have to set
set breed
to new breed,
OK,
And this logic Oops,
this logic just goes away
here also
I'll have to use a set image link to image link
right
which is created and this logic goes away.
OK,
does that make sense
now? Here also, I was using this DEA
breed.
I don't need to use it anymore because I can directly,
you know, consult this particular part.
Yes,
Yes, I know.
Plus three in the chart, if you understand what happened to you.
Yes,
I know
who.
Good.
Ok,
OK,
Anything else which is remaining in this function, which which I need to convert.
OK, so these hooks which are there I need to convert
so to convert them what I need to have is instead I'll have to have a use effect
inside my use effect.
What I will do is I will do a render dog image. OK? Please do this
and use the breed which is there
ok,
and do this only when the breed changes.
OK,
do this only when the breed changes.
Right? So if the breed is not equal to the new breed, then only perform this function
right?
And
generally this is
called the really after,
right?
This is general generally the trend, right?
So you you call all the use effects near to
your return wherever you are trying to return it.
OK, so this is generally the rule.
Uh, originally the convention, which is followed.
OK, finally I'll do an export default.
Uh, dog picks
with hooks.
Right?
Uh, I think I've converted almost everything.
Which is, which was asked asked of me here
into hooks, and I will call this inside. My
dog picks with books,
right?
And I'll hide this one.
I don't need it anymore.
Let me bring my
function in here
when the review in here.
And see if this works or not.
OK, so if I change the breed,
I can get the
beagles right.
And if I change it to Husky, I should get husky images.
Does that make sense to everyone?
Right. If I change it to random,
I should get a random image.
OK,
plus five, if you understand. Basically plus four was for,
uh, plus four, if you understand the hooks,
this this use effect
and plus five, if you understand everything
from from starts to the bottom,
Right. So this is our hooks way of doing things,
right? This is our hooks way of converting what we?
We We were doing with this particular part,
ok?
Does that make sense to everyone?
Who?
Ok,
brilliant. Brilliant, Brilliant. Brilliant.
cool people.
I mean,
that was
all
for today's session,
right?
And thanks a lot for joining in. I believe you learned something new
and the session was insightful for you,
right? We are 24 people in here. I would at least qu
responses in the feedback form which I have posted the link to in the chart.
OK,
once you,
uh, done just fill in the feedback form and then you can drop off.
We'll meet on Saturday.
All right.
Uh, I'm actually running late for something, so I'll probably drop off also.
Right?
Uh,
any doubts we can take up on the next session, if that's possible,
OK?
Or or you can just place it in the lap
or so the
can help you out. If there's anything,
does that make sense to everyone?
Is it cool?
Do people hear me?
Ok,
thanks a lot for joining in for today's session.
Bye bye. And good night.
We'll meet on, uh, the next session which will be on I believe Saturday.
All right, So we'll meet on Saturdays. Session.
I hope you learned something new and valuable today.
Please get to share Share your feedback with us,
OK? So that we can understand what you like.
What you did not like what we can improve what we cannot
right and all that.
Ok, then
I'll stop sharing my screen.
And I would request you all to just
fill in the feedback form before you leave.
Yeah,
Uh,
I just mentioned this to the team. I also I already mentioned this to the team,
but
please do mention this to
them as well, Like on yourself. So I have also already done.
I only did it
right,
but I mean, that would be the best that you can do, I believe. Then
you can can think them again if you want.
I think that would be
no harm.
OK,
I already dropped in a message that day and
they said that they will look into something but
I do not see that part. So I cannot
you know
that's not into my jurisdiction. Actually,
you fill in the feedback form
so that we can
to
decision quality
for you all.
Ok,